Guide to the Adler hip hop archive, circa 1970-2013.
Adler hip hop archive
- Series III. Records and Other Media
  - DVDs
    - WS50: The Video Album, 2004; DVD-1169 (Box 44)
Lemmens, MaryJo. - Xzibit / MaryJo Lemmens. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest, c2008. - Rare Books ML3930.X95 L46 2008
Lemmens, MaryJo. - Cypress Hill / Mary Jo Lemmens. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest, c2008. Electronic Access: http://catdir.loc.gov/catdir/toc/ecip0724/2007031167.html - Rare Books ML421.C975 L46 2008
Lewis, Miles Marshall, 1970- - Scars of the soul are why kids wear bandages when they don't have bruises / Miles Marshall Lewis. - New York: Akashic Books, c2004. - Rare Books F128.68.B8 L49 2004
Light, Alan. - The skills to pay the bills: the story of the Beastie Boys / Alan Light. - New York: Three Rivers Press, c2005. - Rare Books ML421.B365 L54 2005
Liles, Kevin. - Make it happen: the hip hop generation guide to success / Kevin Liles; with Samantha Marshall. - New York: Atria Books, 2006, c2005. - Rare Books HF5386 .L595 2006
LL Cool J, 1968- - I make my own rules / LL Cool J with Karen Hunter. - New York, NY: St. Martin's Press, 1997. - Rare Books ML420.L14 A3 1997b
LL Cool J, 1968- - I make my own rules / LL Cool J with Karen Hunter. - New York: St. Martin's Paperbacks, 1998, c1997. - Rare Books ML420.L14 A3 1998
Mansfield, Joe, compiler, author. - Beat box: a drum machine obsession / compiled and written by Joe Mansfield. - Malden, MA: Get On Down, 2013. - Rare Books MT724.5 .M36 2013 ++ - Accompanied by press release and card with code for downloading tracks.
Marcovitz, Hal. - Notorious B.I.G. / Hal Marcovitz. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books ML420.N76 M37 2007
Marcovitz, Hal. - Dr. Dre / Hal Marcovitz. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books ML420.D78 M37 2007
Marcovitz, Hal. - 50 Cent / Hal Marcovitz. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest, c2008. - Rare Books ML420.F54 M37 2007
Marsh, Dave. - Sun City by Artists United Against Apartheid, the struggle for freedom in South Africa: the making of the record / by Dave Marsh. - New York, N.Y.: Penguin Books, 1985. - Rare Books ML421.A78 M36+
Mase (Vocalist) - Revelations: there's a light after the lime / Pastor Mason Betha with Karen Hunter. - New York: Pocket Books, c2001. - Rare Books BR1725.M27 A3 2001
Mattern, Joanne, 1963- - Eminem / Joanne Mattern. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books ML420.E53 M38 2007
Morano, Aye Jay. - Gangsta rap coloring book / [Aye Jay; foreword by J-Zone; afterword by Sacha Jenkins]. - San Francisco, Calif.: Last Gasp, c2004. - Rare Books ML394 .J39 2004+
Morgan, Joan. - When chickenheads come home to roost: my life as a hip-hop feminist / Joan Morgan. - New York: Simon & Schuster, c1999. - Rare Books E185.86 .M63 1999
Myrie, Russell. - Don't rhyme for the sake of riddlin': the authorised story of Public Enemy / Russell Myrie. - Edinburgh; New York: Canongate, 2009. - Rare Books ML421.P82 M97 2009
Ogg, Alex. - The men behind Def Jam: the radical rise of Russell Simmons & Rick Rubin / Alex Ogg. - London: Omnibus, 2002. - Rare Books ML429.S56 O5 2002
Oliver, Richard W., 1946- - Hip-hop, inc.: success strategies of the rap moguls / Richard Oliver, Tim Leffel. - New York, NY: Thunder's Mouth Press, 2006. - Rare Books ML3790 .O48 2006
Osse´, Reggie. - Bling: the hip-hop jewelry book / Reggie Osse´ & Gabriel A. Tolliver. - New York: Bloomsbury: Distributed to the trade by Holtzbrinck Publishers, c2006. Electronic Access: http://catdir.loc.gov/catdir/enhancements/fy0667/2006043051 -b.html http://catdir.loc.gov/catdir/enhancements/fy0667/2006043051 -d.html - Rare Books NK7310.3.H57 O88 2006 - With dust jacket. Authors' signed presentation copy to Bill Adler.
Palmer, Tamara. - Country fried soul: adventures in Dirty South hip-hop / Tamara Palmer. - San Francisco, CA: Backbeat, 2005. - Rare Books ML3531 .P35 2005
Percelay, James. - Double snaps / James L. Percelay, Stephan Dweck, Monteria Ivey. - New York: Quill, c1995. - Rare Books PN6231.N5 P46 1995
Pereira, Al. - Rappers' delights: African-American cookin' with soul / by Al Pereira. - New York, N.Y.: Universe, 1998. - Rare Books TX715 .P466 1998 - Inscribed to Bill Adler by the author.
Perry, Imani, 1972- - Prophets of the hood: politics and poetics in hip hop / Imani Perry. - Durham: Duke University Press, 2004. - Rare Books ML3531 .P47 2004
Powell, Ricky. - The Rickford files: classic New York photographs / by Ricky Powell; foreword by Sacha Jenkins. - New York: St Martin's Griffin, c2000. - Rare Books TR681.F3 P69 2000+
Powell, Ricky. - Oh snap!: the rap photography of Ricky Powell. - New York: St. Martin's Griffin, 1998. - Rare Books ML87 .P82 1998+
Powell, Ricky. - Public access: Ricky Powell photographs, 1985-2005 / texts by Ricky Powell ... [et al.]. - New York, NY: PowerHouse Books, 2005. - Rare Books TR681.F3 P695 2005+ - Author's signed presentation copy to Bill Adler.
Price, Emmett George. - Hip hop culture / Emmett G. Price III. - Santa Barbara, Calif.: ABC-CLIO, c2006. - Rare Books ML3531 .P75 2006
Professor Griff (Musician) - Analytixz: 20 years of conversations and enter-views with Public Enemy's Minista of Information / Professor Griff. - [Atlanta, GA]: Heirz to the Shah Publishing: RATHSI, c2009. - Rare Books ML421.P82 P76 2009
Queen Latifah, 1970- - Queen of the scene / by Queen Latifah; illustrated by Frank Morrison. - New York: Laura Geringer Books, c2006. - Rare Books PZ8.3.L34444 Q44 2006+ - Disk lacking.
Queen Pen. - Situations: a book of short stories / Lynise "QueenPen" Walters. - [S.l.]: QP Publications, 2002, c2001. - Rare Books PS3617.U444 S58 - Signed by the author.
Reeves, Marcus, 1969- - Somebody scream!: rap music's rise to prominence in the aftershock of Black power / Marcus Reeves. - New York: Faber and Faber, 2008. Electronic Access: http://www.loc.gov/catdir/enhancements/fy0743/2007036129-b. html http://www.loc.gov/catdir/enhancements/fy0743/2007036129-d. html - Rare Books ML3531 .R44 2008
Ro, Ronin. - Have gun will travel: the spectacular rise and violent fall of Death Row Records / Ronin Ro. - New York: Broadway Books, 2000, c1998. - Rare Books ML3790 .R6 2000
Ro, Ronin. - Street sweeper / Ronin Ro. - Los Angeles, CA: [S] Affilliated, 2000. - Rare Books PS3568.O14 S77 2000
Ro, Ronin. - Gangsta: merchandizing the rhymes of violence / Ronin Ro. - New York: St. Martin's Press, 1996. - Rare Books ML3531 .R78
Ro, Ronin. - Raising hell: the reign, ruin, and redemption of Run-D.M.C. and Jam Master Jay / Ronin Ro. - New York: Amistad, c2005. - Rare Books ML400 .R65
Rockworth, Janice. - Wu-Tang Clan / Janice Rockworth. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest, c2008. Electronic Access: http://catdir.loc.gov/catdir/toc/ecip0724/2007032968.html - Rare Books ML421.W98 R63 2008
Rodriguez, K. S. - Will Smith: from Fresh prince to king of cool / K. S. Rodriguez. - New York: HarperCollinsPublishers, c1998. - Rare Books PN2287.S612 R64 1998
Sanna, E. J. - Lloyd Banks / E.J. Sanna. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2008. - Rare Books ML420.B23 S36 2008
Sarig, Roni. - Third coast: OutKast, Timbaland, and how hip-hop became a southern thing / Roni Sarig; photographs by Julia Beverly. - Cambridge, MA: Da Capo Press, 2007. - Rare Books ML3531 .S27 2007
Schmelling, Michael, 1973- - Atlanta: hip hop and the South / photographs by Michael Schmelling; text by Kelefa Sanneh; interviews by Will Welch. - San Francisco, CA: Chronicle Books, c2010. - Rare Books ML3531 .S37 2010 - Signed by the authors and photgrapher. With dust jacket.
Scott, Celicia, 1957- - Ludacris / Celicia Scott. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books ML420.L85 S36 2007
Scott, Damion. - How to draw hip-hop / Damion Scott and Kris Ex. - New York: Watson-Guptill, 2006. - Rare Books NC825.H57 S36 2006+
Shabazz, David L. - Dolemite: the story of Rudy Ray Moore / David L. Shabazz & Julian L.D. Shabazz; with the cooperation and assistance of Rudy Ray Moore. - Clinton, SC: Awesome Records, c1996. - Rare Books PN2287.M6973 S52 1996
Shabazz, Jamel, 1960- - A time before crack / Jamel Shabazz; essays by Charlie Ahearn and Terrence Jennings; introduction by Claude Grunitzky; afterword by James "Koe" Rodriguez. - New York: powerHouse Books, 2005. - Rare Books TR659.8 .S53 2005+
Simmons, Danny. - '85: a novel / Danny Simmons, Floyd Hughes. - New York: Atria Books, 2008. Electronic Access: http://www.loc.gov/catdir/enhancements/fy0805/2007016672-d. html - Rare Books PN6727.S51575 A15 2008
Simmons, Joseph. - It's like that: a spiritual memoir / Joseph "Reverend Run" Simmons with Curtis L. Taylor. - New York: St. Martin's Press, c2000. - Rare Books BR1725.S4675 A3 2000
Simmons, Kimora Lee. - Fabulosity: what it is & how to get it / Kimora Lee Simmons. - New York: ReganBooks, c2006. - Rare Books HQ1206 .S543 2006
Simmons, Russell. - Do you!: 12 laws to access the power in you to achieve happiness and success / Russell Simmons; with Chris Morrow; [foreword by Donald Trump]. - New York: Gotham Books, c2007. - Rare Books BF637.S4 S5485 2007
Simmons, Russell. - Life and Def: sex, drugs, money, and God / Russell Simmons with Nelson George. - New York, N.Y.: Crown Publishers, c2001. - Rare Books ML429.S56 A3 2001
Simone, Jacquelyn. - OutKast / Jacquelyn Simone. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest, c2008. - Rare Books ML3930.O9 S56 2008
Smallman, Jake. - Stencil graffiti capital: Melbourne / Jake Smallman & Carl Nyman. - West New York, NJ: Mark Batty, c2005. - Rare Books NK8654 .S62 2005
Smash, Nick. - Hip hop 86-89 / by Nick Smash. - Woodford Green, Essex, England: International Music Publications, c1990. - Rare Books ML3531 .S63 1990 ++
Snoop Dogg, 1972- - Tha Doggfather: the times, trials, and hardcore truths of Snoop Dogg / Snoop Dogg, with Davin Seay. - New York: William Morrow, c1999. - Rare Books ML420.S665 A3 1999b
Souljah, Sister. - The coldest winter ever / Sister Souljah. - New York: Washington Square Press: Published by Pocket Books, 2001, c1999. - Rare Books PS3569.O7374 C6 2001
Souljah, Sister. - No disrespect / Sister Souljah. - New York: Vintage Books, 1996. - Rare Books E185.86 .S67 1996
Stancell, Steven. - Rap whoz who: the world of rap music / Steven Stancell. - New York: Schirmer Books, c1996. - Rare Books ML400 .S77 1996+
Stauffer, Stacey, 1973- - Will Smith / Stacey Stauffer. - Philadelphia, Pa.: Chelsea House Publishers, c1999. - Rare Books PN2287.S612 S72 1998
Tate, Greg. - Flyboy in the buttermilk: essays on contemporary America / Greg Tate. [Foreword by Henry Louis Gates, Jr.] - New York: Simon & Schuster, c1992. - Rare Books E185.615 .T22
Thigpen, David E. - Jam Master Jay: the heart of hip hop / David E. Thigpen. - New York: Pocket Star Books, c2003. - Rare Books ML420.J228 T47 2003
Toop, David. - Rap attack 3: African rap to global hip hop / David Toop. - London: Serpent's Tail, 2000. - Rare Books ML3531 .T66 2000
Toure´, 1971- - Never drank the kool-aid: essays / Toure´. - New York: Picador, 2006. - Rare Books E169.12 .T665 2006
Va¨isa¨nen, Mika. - And it don't stop: Hip Hop photography by Mika. - Berlin: Schwarzkopf & Schwarzkopf, c2004. - Rare Books ML87 .V32 2004 ++ - Author's signed presentation copy to Bill Adler. With dust jacket.
Vanilla Ice. - Ice by Ice / Vanilla Ice. - New York: Avon Books, c1991. - Rare Books ML420.V274 A3 1991
Walker, Steven Akili, author. - Turn the horns on / by Steven Akili Walker with ElizaBeth Felton... - New York, N.Y.: Wynter-Lynn Publishing, 2011. - Rare Books ML420.W18 A3 - Inscribed by Akili Walker to Bill Adler.
Wallace, Voletta. - Biggie: Voletta Wallace remembers her son / with Tremell McKenzie; poetry by Voletta Wallace. - New York: Atria Books, 2005. - Rare Books ML420.N76 W35 2005
Waters, Rosa, 1957- - Yung Joc / Rosa Waters. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2008. - Rare Books ML420.Y86 W38 2008
Weiner, Chuck. - Eminem: in his own words / Chuck Weiner. - London: Omnibus Press, c2001. - Rare Books ML420.E53 E65 2001
Weingarten, Christopher R. - It takes a nation of millions to hold us back / Christopher R. Weingarten. - New York: Continuum, c2010. - Rare Books ML421.P82 W45 2010
Woldu, Gail Hilson. - The words and music of Ice Cube / Gail Hilson Woldu. - Westport, Conn.: Praeger, 2008. - Rare Books ML420.I29 W66 2008
Young, Kevin. - The grey album; on the blackness of blackness / Kevin Young. - Minneapolis, Minn.: Graywolf Press, c2012. - Rare Books NX512.3.A35 Y68 2012 - Inscribed by the author to Bill Adler.